<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: kwanmukan | Evan P. Mills' Ramblings]]></title>
  <link href="http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/blog/categories/kwanmukan/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-16T22:27:18-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Evan P. Mills]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keiko Diary for 2006-10-24]]></title>
    <link href="http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/blog/2006/10/27/keiko-diary-for-2006-10-24/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-27T06:08:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/blog/2006/10/27/keiko-diary-for-2006-10-24</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earned my brown belt!</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Led the Kwanbu Kihon and Heian Shodan katas, demonstrated Heian Godon, ipon
kumite, hit-move-hit, line drills.</p>

<p>Showed improved flexibility, strong spirit and proper breathing throughout
Heian 5.  Need to improve timing of the end of actions (e.g. the foot landing
at the same moment and the double knife hand completes).</p>

<p>Big thanks to Sensei Hudson!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keiko Diary for 2006-Apr-25]]></title>
    <link href="http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/blog/2006/04/26/keiko-diary-for-2006-apr-25/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-26T11:58:15-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/blog/2006/04/26/keiko-diary-for-2006-apr-25</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today's workout was just that -- a <strong>workout</strong>.  The emphasis was on keeping
our bodies in motion without many breaks.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>During the mixed session, most of the time was spent with the kids doing
arious kicks against a pad.  They performed front, side, scissor, crescent and
reverse crescent kicks.  We ended up with flying drift kicks performed while
running full speed and jumping over a stick.</p>

<p>Another emphasis was staying in a horse stance for quite a while.  Knees say,
"ouch."</p>

<p>For the adult session, we did conditioning (20/20/20 crunches front/right/left)
and 45 pushups (5+10+15+10+5).  And we ended with Haien Sandan performed as
practice, all power, all speed and correct dynamics.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keiko Diary for 2006-Apr-18]]></title>
    <link href="http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/blog/2006/04/19/keiko-diary-for-2006-apr-18/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-19T10:58:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/blog/2006/04/19/keiko-diary-for-2006-apr-18</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Themes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Speed vs. Power</li>
<li>Circular Into Linear Motion</li>
<li>Oblique Fighting Defense and Counter</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<p>First, we practiced low, inside middle, outside middle and upper defends, once
with ten reps per side with speed and technique but not emphasizing power,
then with five reps per side with technique and power.  The speed reps are
aerobic.</p>

<p>Secondly, we worked on moving from a circular motion to a linear motion.  We
executed a crescent kick (circular motion) but instead of continuing the
rotation to perform a spin kick we instead paused, lifetd the leg towards the
chest and executed a side kick (linear motion). Moving from one motion to the
other requires good balance and strength to halt the spin.</p>

<p>Thirdly, we worked on defending against a lunge punch using a move to the
oblique.  Starting in a closed stance, the attacker starts the step and lunge
punch.  The defender rotates the front foot back and behind (ala the plus
pattern) while executing an outside-inside middle defend against the punch.
This defend is more of a parry than a full block as the intent is simply to
avoid the punch to the face.   Finally, the defender steps in, lowers (ala
ipon kumite #1), twists and delivers a punch to the attacker's side.  The
defender should ensure the non-punching hand is raised to protect the side of
the head.  To counter the defense, the attacker can rotate the punching hand
downward to defend the counterpunch, step the oblique and punch to the head or
side.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keiko Diary for 2006-Apr-11]]></title>
    <link href="http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/blog/2006/04/12/keiko-diary-for-2006-apr-11/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-12T09:38:59-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/blog/2006/04/12/keiko-diary-for-2006-apr-11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There is no keiko diary for April 11th.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Instead of the three <em>other</em> things I was supposed to do last night we went
with B, R, H &amp; N to see
<a href="http://www.mccoyrigby.com/cbiofrm.html" title="Cathy Rigby">Cathy Rigby</a> in her
farewell performance of <a href="http://www.peter-pan.com/" title="Peter Pan">Peter Pan</a> at
the <a href="http://www.cincinnatiarts.org/venues/aronoff/" title="The Aronoff Center for the Arts">Aronoff</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keiko Diary for 2006-Apr-04]]></title>
    <link href="http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/blog/2006/04/05/keiko-diary-for-2006-apr-04/"/>
    <updated>2006-04-05T11:26:23-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://geneticgrabbag.github.com/blog/2006/04/05/keiko-diary-for-2006-apr-04</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the first of my keiko (karate practice) diary entries.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Sensei took advantage of the fact that no little kids were there to
concentrate on training and conditioning.  <em>Everyone</em> did stairstepped
pushups, kicking line drills and practicing moving into an oblique position by
taking a fighting stance, moving the back foot up (without raising the head)
and moving the other foot back so that the body is on a 45&deg; angle.</p>

<p>We worked on basic fighting technique, specifically using the swap-jump to
better position ourselves for a counterattack.</p>

<ol>
<li>Attacker and defender in closed fighting stances.</li>
<li>Attacker reverse punches to chest.</li>
<li>Defender perries punch downward while sliding back (ala ipon kumite #3).</li>
<li>Attacker uses swap-jump to position obliquely while raising an easy middle
defend.  Attacker then steps in, lowers and attacks ribs.</li>
</ol>


<p>We also studied a few terms:</p>

<dl>
    <dt>Atemi</dt>
    <dd>Vital strike.  "Soft target" one can hit to down an attacker</dd>
    <dt>Kime</dt>
    <dd>Focus</dd>
    <dt>Mai-ai</dt>
    <dd>Interval.  Maintaining the proper distance with an opponent</dd>
    <dt>Zanshin</dt>
    <dd>
        Remaining mind;  After finishing an action, keeping concentration for
        what might happen next
    </dd>
</dl>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
